DAVE BOUCHARD

Calgary, AB | 403.471.4290 | davidjbouchard@gmail.com | bouchardgis.github.io

CAREER PROFILE

Technologist with 6 years of experience implementing technologies for the energy, manufacturing and environmental sectors, with 2 years of GIS-specific experience. Developed and managed automation solutions for data analysis - and their associated systems - for small teams (5-10 people) and larger enterprises.

Core competencies include: Continuous Learning, Teamwork, Strong Initiative, Project Management, Client Relations, Versatile, Ambitious, Coding. Educational credentials include a degree in GIS from SAIT Polytechnic.

EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2019

Systems Tech & IT Analyst, Data Scavenger, Calgary, AB

- Managed 2 custom GIS applications; designed, acquired, constructed, enhanced, and implemented any changes to the applications, including any data consolidation
- Ensured quality control, job organization and tracking of plans for over 50 projects
- Created, updated, and managed geospatial data layers with our documented standards
- Grew my skillset with every new project, staying up to date on new technologies
- Responsible for management and quality of maps production in SCADA software, along with associated datasets
- Eagerly participated in the development and maintenance of processes, tools, methodologies and automation processes for 6 software products

2015 - 2017

Technical Consultant, Contract, Calgary, AB

- Built relationships with clients, while also organizing and managing their datasets and devices
- Developed project scopes, budgets, schedules and deliverables for dozens of projects
- Delivered assigned GIS (and other) project deliverables on time and on budget
- Efficiently organized and managed GIS datasets for client projects; collected, manipulated, analyzed and presented spatial information
- Crafted well-designed and easy-to-read maps and map templates, as needed, for clients

2013 - 2015

Programmer, Field Aviation, Calgary, AB

- Worked with operators, planners, and quality assurance teams to ensure over 3500 different aircraft parts were manufactured to client specifications
- Improved the efficiency of existing manufacturing programs by over 50%

SKILLS

Esri suite and ArcGIS (Pro, Online, Collector and Survey123), Coding Languages (Python, VBA, SQL), AutoCAD, Point cloud data handling, Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Suite (Illustrator)

EDUCATION

2018

SAIT Polytechnic, Alberta

Bachelor of Applied Technology in GIS with Honours